Guide to the Faculty of Arts and Sciences, Yale University, Photographs
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Faculty of Arts and Sciences, Yale University, photographs
1930-1970
RU 1093
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.5
(1 box)
The materials consist of photographs of various Yale faculty members, offices, events, and memorabilia.
Yale University. Faculty of Arts and Sciences
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 14-A (YRG 14-A), Records of governing bodies and committees of the Yale Faculty of Arts and Sciences.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Originally classed as part of Yale publications collection.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Faculty members holding appointments in the academic departments of both Yale College and the Graduate School together constitute the Faculty of Arts and Sciences. Within this Faculty there are four divisions: the division of the biological sciences, the division of the humanities, the division of the social sciences, and the division of the physical sciences and engineering.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of photographs of various Yale faculty members, offices, events, and memorabilia.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by subject.
College teachers; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Faculty; Photographs; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. Faculty of Arts and Sciences
- Faculty of Arts and Sciences Photographs, 1930-1970; Accession 2010-A-003; 0.5
  - Faculty Garden Party, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Faculty meeting group pictures, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Architecture, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Biology Department faculty, 1923-1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Chemistry Department faculty, 1923-1940 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Classics Department: Dedication Exercises at Phelps, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Drama School Faculty, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - English Department faculty, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Geology Department faculty and expeditions, 1938-1953 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - German Department faculty, 1938-1958 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - History Deparment faculty, 1930-1938 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - History of Art Department faculty, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Mathematics Department faculty, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Physics Department faculty, 1920-1951 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Pathology Department Institute of Human Relations, 1921-1941 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Spanish Department faculty, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Zoology Department faculty, Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - First Directed Studies group, Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Unidentified faculty and staff, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - School of Organization and Management opening ceremonies, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Social Science faculty, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Objects and Memorabilia
    - Historical Artifacts (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Inscriptions and plaques (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Microscope and telescope (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Plates (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Silver (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Wooden Spoon (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 28)